<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Irene Kowal</title>
    <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Irene Kowal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 13:07:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.irenakowal.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/welcome</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 13:07:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/welcome</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my personal site where you will find a collection of photos from the productions of my plays, reviews&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;about my plays and novella, a short video of my work as well as my own thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to contact me through the links on the left.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaced - to be brief</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/displaced---to-be-brief</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/displaced---to-be-brief</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DISPLACED
An American and Ukrainian are drawn to one another the first time they meet in Moscow in 1969. Orest and Irena are brother and sister in their twenties, about to spend August travelling through Soviet Ukraine with a tourist group, a trip that will change their lives forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A beautiful, naïve and shy Irena is hungry for adventure. Having lived a sheltered, academic existence up to now, she begins to forge her own ideas about the Soviet world around her. In her brother’s eyes, she wakes up to her own womanhood. Orest grows to love Irena as a sister but secretly wants her as a woman. When two KGB agents attempt to engage Irena in espionage, Orest is the pawn and Irena must make an agonizing choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month is framed by multiple flashbacks beginning with a wrenching decision to leave the infant Orest with his grandparents as the parents escape from Soviet Ukraine during WWII. Scenes reveal the horrors wrought by war and the Soviet occupation, their grandparents’ exile to Siberia, the turmoil of immigrant life in the Germany and the United States, the tortured relationship between their parents, Josef and Marusia, and the contrasting milieus in which Irena and Orest grow up.
Humorous, satiric episodes offer a respite to the overwhelming, profound tragedy of a family’s disintegration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DISPLACED, an autobiographical novel, a story of abandonment, loss, upheaval and reconciliation. It creates a magical world in which everything is dislocated: time, identity, love, country and allegiance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/about-me</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/about-me</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Born in a refugee camp in postwar Germany, raised and educated in the United States, Irena Kowal moved to Kyiv, Ukraine in the mid 1990&amp;rsquo;s and fully embraced her literary calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irena Kowal (pen name) Irene Kowal (legal name) holds a Master of Arts in English and American Literature from the University of Connecticut. She taught English in Paris and English and journalism in Massachusetts. She pursued a graduate degree in comparative literature at the University of East Anglia,England.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1990-2005 she lived in Frankfurt,London and Kyiv. Kowal&amp;rsquo;s play, initially entitled PAGAN SAINTS and subsequently titled, THE LION AND THE LIONESS, had a rehearsed reading at London&amp;rsquo;s Soho theatre in 2001. The play, written in English and subsequently translated into Ukrainian, premiered in Kyiv in 2001 amid much controversy. It starred the legendary actor Bohdan Stupka. The production went on tour to nine Ukrainian cities, was invited by the mayor of Krakow and participated in an international festival in Gdansk. In October, 2007 THE LION AND THE LIONESS premiered at the National Theatre in Kyiv where it played in repertory until Bohdan Stupka&amp;rsquo;s death in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1995 to 1998 she worked as a freelance journalist for BBC Ukraine. In 1999-2000 she participated in a drama workshop at the Chelsea Theatre in London where she wrote a draft of THE MARINATED ARISTOCRAT. In 2002 she organized and funded a drama conference in Kyiv with British dramatists and Ukrainian playwrights and directors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May,2004 Kowal&amp;rsquo;s play THE MARINATED ARISTOCRAT premiered in Kyiv with the prominent actor Alexei Vertynsky starring in the main role. It has been playing in repertory for twelve years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October, 2007 THE LION AND THE LIONESS and THE MARINATED ARISTOCRAT were published in a bi-lingual Ukrainian/English edition with a grant from the American Embassy in Kyiv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her novella entitled THE BAREFOOT BALLERINA received a grant from the American Embassy in Kyiv, was translated into Ukrainian, and published by Duliby press. THe first edition has been sold out. The novella is currently being adapted into a ballet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapters of her autobiographical novel DISPLACED were well received during a reading at Harvard University on March 20,2012. The novel will be published in late
May,2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kyiv television production company Zoloti Vorota madea film of Kowal&amp;rsquo;s play THE LION AND THE LIONESS staged at Kyiv&amp;rsquo;s National Theatre. The film has been screened at Harvard University, Washington D.C. and Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has written, produced and choreographed three tableaux for the 200th birthday of the Ukrainian bard Taras Shevchenko. The concert was held at the Longy School of Music, Cambridge, MA on March 15, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, she is also working on a commissioned play entitled WOMAN IN TWO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example post of what an interview</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/example-post-of-what-an-interview</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/example-post-of-what-an-interview</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example for plays</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/example-for-plays</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/example-for-plays</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example of a book</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/example-of-a-book</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/example-of-a-book</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example post for books</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/example-post-for-books</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/example-post-for-books</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing-this-post-for-books:4764ee945f59da76a3400be7a8b931dc&#34;&gt;Testing this post for books&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Images</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/images</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/images</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is still an experimental work in progress. Working on organizing and orchestrating the pictures below. Will currently maintain the current page as an archival repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.irenakowal.com/static/images/thumb_IMG_3934_1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image-1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.irenakowal.com/static/images/thumb_IMG_3935_1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image-2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.irenakowal.com/static/images/thumb_IMG_3936_1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image-3&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.irenakowal.com/static/images/thumb_IMG_3937_1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image-4&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lion and the Lioness</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/lion-and-the-lioness</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 13:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/lion-and-the-lioness</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My play, THE LION AND THE LIONESS, a tragicomedy, is based on the diaries of Lev and Sonia Tolstoy kept for 48 years of their tempestuous marriage. The strucutre is cyclical, using the technique of reverse chronology to explore the couple&amp;rsquo;s relationship, starting with Tolstoy&amp;rsquo;s death in 1910 and ending on the night before the couple&amp;rsquo;s wedding in 1862. The appearance of two hooligan characters provides a sly, running commentary on the drama of the two titanic figures at the center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE LION AND THE LIONESS continues to be immensely popular because, as Valentyna Hrytsuk wrote in &amp;ldquo;Slaivc and East European Performance&amp;rdquo; magaize, &amp;ldquo;the audience is first drawn to the theme of contemporary marriage, the eternal conflict between a man and woman&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>