<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biography on Irene Kowal</title>
    <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/categories/biography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biography on Irene Kowal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 13:47:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.irenakowal.com/categories/biography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/about-me</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 13:47:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/about-me</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Born in a refugee camp in postwar Germany, raised and educated in the United States, Irena Kowal moved to Kyiv, Ukraine in the mid 1990&amp;rsquo;s and fully embraced her literary calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irena Kowal (pen name) Irene Kowal (legal name) holds a Master of Arts in English and American Literature from the University of Connecticut. She taught English in Paris and English and journalism in Massachusetts. She pursued a graduate degree in comparative literature at the University of East Anglia, England. From 1995 to 1998 she worked as a journalist for BBC Ukraine. In 1999-2000 she participated in a drama workshop at the Chelsea Theatre in London. In 2002 she organized and funded a drama conference in Kyiv with British dramatists and Ukrainian playwrights and directors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1990-2005 she lived in Frankfurt, London and Kyiv. Kowal&amp;rsquo;s play, initially entitled PAGAN SAINTS and subsequently titled, THE LION AND THE LIONESS, had a rehearsed reading at London&amp;rsquo;s Soho theatre in 2001. The play, written in English and subsequently tranlsated into Ukrainian premiered in Kyiv in 2001 amid much controversy. It starred the legendary actor Bohdan Stupka. The production went on tour to nine Ukrainian cities, was invited by the mayor of Krakow and participated in an international festival in Gdansk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October, 2007 THE LION AND THE LIONESS premiered at the National Theatre in Kyiv where it played in repertory until Bohdan Stupka&amp;rsquo;s death in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May, 2004 Kowal&amp;rsquo;s play THE MARINATED ARISTOCRAT premiered in Kyiv with the prominent actor Alexei Vertynsky starring in the main role. It has been playing in repertory for nine years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October, 2007 THE LION AND THE LIONESS and THE MARINATED ARISTOCRAT were published in a bi-lingual Ukrainian/English edition with a grant from the American Embassy in Kyiv.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her novella entitled THE BALLERINA WHO LOST HER POINTE SHOES recieved a grant from the American Embassy in Kyiv, was translated into Ukrainian, and publish by Duliby press. THe first edition has been sold out. The Ukrainian composer Myroslav Skoryk and artistic director of Kyiv&amp;rsquo;s National Opera and Ballet is writing a musical score for a ballet based on the novella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chapters of her autobiographical novel DISPLACED had ba well recieved reading at Harvard University on March 20,2012. The novel is near completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Kyiv television production company Zoloti Vorota madea film of Kowal&amp;rsquo;s play THE LION AND THE LIONESS staged at Kyiv&amp;rsquo;s National Theatre. The film has been screened at Harvard University, Washington D.C. and will be shown in Chicago at the Ukrainian museum on February 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently she is working on two additional literary projects. She has written three tableaux for the 200th birthday of Ukrainian bard Taras Shevchenko which will be celebrated at Longy School of Music, Cambridge, MA on March 15, 2014. She is also working on a commissioned play entitled WOMAN IN TWO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>