<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on Irene Kowal</title>
    <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on Irene Kowal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 13:39:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.irenakowal.com/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>In dialogue with British dramaturgy: Irena Kowal Implements Drama conference</title>
      <link>http://www.irenakowal.com/in-dialogue-with-british-dramaturgy-irena-kowal-implements-drama-conference</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 13:39:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.irenakowal.com/in-dialogue-with-british-dramaturgy-irena-kowal-implements-drama-conference</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This [The Marinated Aristocrat] is an extraordinary production of a hilariously funny play which is an acerbic commentary on the post-Soviet reality in Ukraine. Irena Kowal wrote this, her second, play in English, but here, in Kyiv, it is brilliantly staged in a Ukrainian translation at the Molody Theatre, which is well-known for staging more experimental works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The play, written in the tradition of the theatre of the absurd, deals with the culture clash that results when a Ukrainian actor, Boris is encouraged by his ambitious wife (who has an underwear stall at the local market) to seek his fortune overseas. He takes a position as a manservant with an elderly British couple, but quickly discovers that his real position will be to play out roles according to their fantasies. But his own fantasy, fueled by &lt;em&gt;samogon&lt;/em&gt; (homemade vodka), is richer and the tables are turned as he takes control of the  situation. He makes actors out of the old couple, forcing them out of their hidebound roles and bringing them back to their youth. But the role-playing takes over reality, and the old man, who has been dressed up as a hetman, takes the sword-wielding a step too far, and takes the sword to Boris, leaving him dead. The poor actor is then pickled in &lt;em&gt;formaldehyde a la Damien Hurst&lt;/em&gt;, while his wife, now an underwear tycoon back in Ukraine, laments her misplaced ambitions&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many references and illusions to both British and Ukrainian cultures make the play particularly relevant and interesting to those of living in Ukraine. Neither of the reviewers understand Ukrainian, but as fellow-members of the Literature Group with Irena Kowal, we had an opportunity to read the play in English before going to the theatre. The language is rich and wickedly funny, and it was sometimes frustrating to hear the Ukrainian audience roaring with laughter as we only struggled to remember the wit of the lines we had read. But hte production is so visual and dramatic that even those in our group who hadn&amp;rsquo;t read the play, could not help laughing&amp;hellip; The Ukrainian wife stalks the old couple do disco-dancing; the actor dresses up as a dog; overall, the acting is very physical&amp;hellip; The staging is quite impressive, with elemnts of music and dance, although it is hard to recommend going to the theatre in a language you don&amp;rsquo;t understand, in this case it really is worth it. In the humble opinion ofthe reviewers and a crowd of other ex-pats we met on the night, this play is really a class act - worthy of the stages of New York or London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;by-eliza-burnham-and-stellio-aris:a9b460424673ddb26f59fa25e3a86f76&#34;&gt;By Eliza Burnham and Stellio Aris&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>